#### Contact

sunitc@microsoft.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sunitcarpenter (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Machine Learning
Python (Programming Language)
Data Visualization

# **Sunit Carpenter**

Principal Architect - Microsoft 365 & Copilot | UC Berkeley Master of Information and Data Science 2022

Miami, Florida, United States

# Summary

Experienced Architect with 23 years of demonstrated history of working at Microsoft in multiple technical and leadership roles helping commercial/slge/defense customers and partners in planning, managing and deploying Microsoft Azure, Office 365 and other cloud and on-premise technologies. Skilled in Machine Learning, Business Intelligence, Analytics, Modern Work, Application Development, Agile Methodologies, Architecture, Integration, Security & Identity, Azure PAAS/IAAS and Collaboration technologies.

# Experience

Microsoft

26 years 1 month

Architect - Microsoft 365 Copilot

July 2024 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Provide cutting edge solutions AI solutions for the modern workplace, empowering customers to work smarter and faster with Microsoft 365 & Copilot.

Architect - Data and Artificial Intelligence August 2022 - July 2024 (2 years)

Miami, Florida, United States

- Provide solution architecture and technical consultation on data science, machine learning, and business intelligence for Microsoft Federal government customers.
- Assist customers on their digital transformation both in the cloud and into machine learning on the Azure platform.

Domain Delivery Architect March 2019 - July 2022 (3 years 5 months) Ft Lauderdale, FL Worked with large Federal Government customers to help them migrate their on-premise LOB applications and SharePoint repositories to Azure and O365 respectively.

### Principal Consultant

January 2012 - February 2019 (7 years 2 months)

Ft. Lauderdale, FL

Worked with Enterprise Customers to plan, build, develop and migrate legacy solutions built on SharePoint 2010/2003/2007 to SPO & Power Platform. Also worked on developing web-based solutions using C#/.Net to modernize legacy web and fat client applications.

### Senior Consultant II

January 2008 - January 2012 (4 years 1 month)

Ft Lauderdale, FL

Led various large customer projects around SharePoint Portal Server involving gathering requirements, built vision/scope documents, built a phased approach roadmap, put together technical specifications and managed development teams, and he has also acted as SharePoint project manager and program manager on various projects.

#### Senior Constultant I

January 2006 - January 2008 (2 years 1 month)

Ft Lauderdale, FL

Led various large customer projects in the K12/Higher Education space around SharePoint Portal Server involving gathering requirements, built vision/scope documents, built a phased approach roadmap, put together technical specifications and managed development teams, and he has also acted as SharePoint project manager and program manager on various projects.

#### Consultant II

January 2004 - December 2006 (3 years)

Los Angeles, CA

Worked with State and Local government customers to plan, build, develop and migrate legacy solutions to the latest version of SharePoint. Also assisted with modernizing legacy web applications.

### Consultant I

January 2002 - January 2004 (2 years 1 month)

Milwaukee, WI

Led many engagements in the Media & Entertainment leveraging Windows Media Server, Windows media Player to assist customers including Korea Telecom (World Cup 2002), Virgin Mega Stores and Paramount studios.

#### Associate Consultant II

January 2001 - January 2002 (1 year 1 month)

Milwaukee, WI

Development lead for Accenture.com rebranding effort from Anderson Consulting. Assisted with design and architecture of the Accenture.com web portal leveraging xml/xslt to render dynamic content.

#### Associate Consultant I

September 1999 - January 2001 (1 year 5 months)

Milwaukee, WI

Development lead for BestBuy.com eCommerce initiative. Assisted with developing coding standards, web user interface guidelines and formalized testing methods for the BestBuy eCommerce site.

# Education

University of California, Berkeley

Master of Science - MS, Master of Information and Data Science · (August 2020 - August 2022)

Marquette University

MS, Electrical and Electronics Engineering (1993 - 1997)

Marquette University

BS, Biomedical/Medical Engineering · (1989 - 1993)